Preliminary Inventory to the Frank Seymoure Ross Papers, 1942-1954
Hoover Institution Archives
Frank Seymoure Ross Papers,
1942-1954
60015
Ross, Frank S. (Frank Seymoure), 1893-1970
20 manuscript boxes, 2 oversize boxes (9.4 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, minutes of meetings, notes, reports, printed matter, and photographs, relating to activities of the U.S. Army Transportation Corps in Europe during World War II
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1960
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
United States. Army--Officers; United States. Army Transport Service; World War, 1939-1945; World War, 1939-1945--Transportation; United States--Armed Forces
Preliminary Inventory
- U.S. Army Transportation Corps, OCOFT, minutes of meetings (Box 1.)
  - April 14, 1943 - June 3, 1944
  - September 17, 1944 - June 30, 1945
  - July 1 - December 3, 1945
- U.S. Army Transportation Corps, minutes of daily conferences
  - June 12 - December 31, 1945
  - January 1 - February 20, 1946
- General Ross' comments on daily meetings
  - April 14, 1943 - May 18, 1944
  - September 17, 1944 - June 29, 1945
- X-Ray files 1-4 (Closed Circuit telephone conferences) (Box 2.)
  - July 24, 1943 - February 27, 1944
  - February 28 - June 21, 1944 (A)
  - February 28 - July 24, 1944 (B)
  - August 10 - October 10, 1944
  - November 5, 1944 - March 10, 1945 (Box 3.)
  - March 29 - August 31, 1945
  - September 1, 1945 - February 12, 1946
- Chronological files
  - May 1 - June 5, 1943
  - May 1 - June 30, 1943
  - June 30 - August 13, 1943
  - July 1 - September 30, 1943 (Box 4.)
  - October 1, 1943 - February 15, 1944
  - February 16 - August 5, 1944
  - August 12 - October 11, 1944
  - August 12 - October 11, 1944 (Box 5.)
  - October 12, 1944 - January 12, 1945
  - January 13 - April 15, 1945
  - April 16 - June 30, 1945
  - July 1 - September 30, 1945 (Box 6.)
  - October 1 - December 31, 1945
  - January 1 - February 15, 1946
- Personal correspondence
  - August 15, 1942 - June 25, 1943
  - January 1 - June 28, 1945
  - June 2 - December 30, 1945
  - Frank S. Ross - Charles P. Gross (Box 7.)
    - July 8, 1942 - June 30, 1943
    - July 1, 1943 - April 19, 1945
    - June 9, 1944 - June 19, 1945
  - Frank S. Ross - James R. Washington
    - June 11, 1942 - June 22, 1943
    - July 3, 1943 - May 26, 1944
    - June 1, 1944 - June 26, 1945
- Ceremonies, speeches and press conferences
  - January 10 - May 3, 1944
  - July 1944 - June 1945
  - July 22 - December 31, 1945
- Commendations
  - June 1943 - June 1944
  - July 1944 - June 1945
  - July 1945
- Directives from headquarters, July 1945 (Box 8.)
- Telegrams, Radiograms, Cablegrams, March 24, 1945 - February 21, 1946
- Marine operations, May 29, 1942 - June 14, 1943
- Marine Operations and Inland Waterways
  - July 6, 1943 - May 25, 1944
  - June 14, 1944 - May 31, 1945
- Water Deployment of U.S. Troops, May 8 - December 31, 1945
- Railways
  - July 1, 1943 - May 17, 1944
  - July 8, 1944 - June 26, 1945
  - July 1, 1945 - February 20, 1946
- Weekly Military Shipments Priority Meetings (Box 9.)
  - March 24 - June 30, 1945
  - July 1, 1945 - January 24, 1946
- Mission, Operating Procedure, Route and Statistics on L. C. Express Hauls, 1944
- "XYZ" Motor Transport Support Plan, 1945
- General Board - U.S. Army Forces in the European Theatre
- Operation, Organization, Supply and Services of the Transportation Corps in Europe, 1944, Study #122
- Military Railway Service, Study #123
- Procedures for the Control of Supply and Personnel Movements, Study #124
- Motor Transport Service as a permanent part of the Transportation Corps,Study #125
- Critique of Logistic Support of the Armies by R.G. Ruppenthal (Box 10.)
- Miscellaneous files
  - 1942 - May 1943
  - June 1943 - June 1944
  - July 1944 - June 1945
- History of the Transportation Corps in the European Theatre of Operations (Box 11.)
  - June 1942 - December 1943
    - Part 1
    - Part 2
    - Part 3
- Historical report on the Transportation Corps in the European Theatre of Operations
  - January - March 1944
  - April - June 1944 (Box 12.)
  - June - September 1944 (Battle of France)
  - October - December 1944
    - Part 1
    - Part 2 (Box 13.)
    - Part 3
  - January - March 1945
    - Part 1
    - Part 2
    - Part 3 (Box 14.)
  - April - June 1945
    - Part 1
    - Part 2 (Box 15.)
    - Part 3
  - June - September 1945 (Box 16.)
    - Part 1
    - Part 2
    - Part 3
    - Part 4 (Box 17.)
  - October 1945
  - November 1945
  - December 1945 (Box 18.)
  - January 1945
  - February 1945 (Box 19.)
- Statistical tables on the Transportation Corps in the European Theatre of Operations, 1942-1945
- Weekly Newsletters
  - Volume 1, October 30, 1944 - June 25, 1945
  - Volume 2, June 25 - December 31, 1945
- Stories of Transportation (Box 20.)
  - Volume 1, October 1, 1944 - June 1, 1945
  - Volume 2, June 1 - December 3, 1945
- Historical Critique of the United Kingdom Overlord Movements, November 1, 1945
- German Railway Operations under the U.S. Army, May 8 - December 31, 1945
- Administrative History of the Operation of the 21st Army Group on the Continent of Europe, June 6, 1944 - May 8, 1945